St. Mary's Court - "Never Too Old to Learn" Oral History Project OHP012
People's Archive, MLK Library
St. Mary's Court - "Never Too Old to Learn" Oral History Project
1992-1993
People's Archive, MLK Library
IONA Senior Services (Washington, D.C.)
OHP012
0.5 Linear feet
2 Boxes
Biographical / Historical
Iona Senior Services was founded in 1975 as Iona House to create programs to provide social services to people surrounding the Tenleytown neighborhood. In 1982, Iona was named a lead agency with the D.C. Office of Aging, which enabled them to take their programs to other sections of the city. St. Mary's Court is a non-profit corporation operating a residential living facility for seniors 62 years of age or older or individuals with accessibility needs. Sponsored by the Episcopal Diocese of Washington, it is financed by the U.S. Department of Housing and Urban Development (HUD). Persons of all racial, ethnic, social, political and religious backgrounds are welcome.
Custodial History
Iona Senior Services conducted these interviews between 1992 and 1993, and donated the tapes and transcripts to the Library in the mid-1990s. There is no deed of gift for this collection, but all interviewee releases are granted to the Library.
Scope and Contents
Between 1992 and 1993, students of the "Never Too Old to Learn" class, sponsored by Iona Senior Service, conducted six oral history interviews. Participants were residents, volunteers, and staff members who were interviewed about their personal and family histories and outlooks on life. All interviewees were from St. Mary's Court, a senior residence facility in Foggy Bottom located at 725 24th Street NW.
Oral History; Medical personnel; Older people
- Series 1: Transcripts
  Scope and Contents
  Materials in this series include transcripts for all interviews.
  - Virginia Allen, 1992 November 20 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Harry F. Conn, 1993 March 1 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Lillian Gordon, 1993 November 10 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Angel Johnson, 1992 November 28 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Florine Jones, 1992 November 3 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Louise Smith, 1992 November 11 (Box 1, Folder 6)
- Series 2: Interviews
  Materials in this series include master copies of the oral histories on audio cassette.
  - Virginia Allen, 1992 November 20 (Box 2, Folder 12-01)
  - Harry F. Conn, 1993 March 1 (Box 2, Folder 12-02)
  - Lillian Gordon, 1993 November 10 (Box 2, Folder 12-03)
  - Angel Johnson, 1992 November 28 (Box 2, Folder 12-04)
  - Florine Jones, 1992 November 3 (Box 2, Folder 12-05)
  - Louise Smith, 1992 November 11 (Box 2, Folder 12-06)